A Guide to the Adèle Goodman Clark papers, 1849-1978
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Series XV: Ephemera and Photographs, 1850s - 1970s
  - Subseries B: Ephemera, 1890s-1950s
    - Scrapbook with miscellaneous newspaper and magazine clippings of poetry and articles on the Confederacy, circa 1908 (Box 232)
    - Richmond calendars with illustrations that include that of Adèle Clark and Nora Houston (Box 232)
    - sheet music (Box 232)
    - Ticket stubs, Governor's Ball tickets, bus receipts, various passes (Box 232)
    - U.S. Senate Chamber passes, 1926-1933 (Box 232)
    - Suffrage Postage Stamp, noteworthy envelopes (Box 232)
    - Driver's permits of Adèle Clark (Box 232)
    - Adèle Clark drawing of Millhiser House/Catholic Woman's Club - 916 W. Franklin St. (Box 232)
    - U.S. Government Thrift Cards, 1923 (Box 232)
    - John Lewis' Richmond Public Library card (901 W. Franklin St.), Nora Houston's membership (Box 232)
    - Wedgwood's Manifold Writer (Box 232)
    - Miscellaneous suffrage and voting rights publications, pamphlets, postcards, fliers, broadsides, calendar, circulars, banners and other literature, much of it printed by the ESLV, suffrage organizations, VLWV and NLWV, 1910s-1930s (Box 233)
    - Art material (Box-folder 233:1)
      Includes children's art work, art club material, instructional material; Japanese print.
    - Blueprints (five) (Box-folder 233:2)
      Two labeled "Class Room Building--State Teacher's College, Farmville, Virginia--Frank F. Stone Architect, Roanoke, Virginia, July 10, 1944"; a third blue print labeled "Improvements to Employees Cottage as suggested by Art Commission, May 5, 1944"; fourth labeled "Temporary Employee Cottage, Division of the Budget, March 29, 1944";drawing for inscription of building "Julian H. Burruss Hall" labeled "Teaching and Admin. Building, Va. Polytechnic Inst., Blacksburg, VA - Carneal, Johnston & Wright Architects & Engineers, Richmond, Virginia."
    - Diplomas (Box-folder 233:2-A)
      Various institutions to Benjamin Franklin Dew Jr., 1930s-1940s.
    - Drawing (Box-folder 233:2-A)
      Entitled "Proposed Store For Mr. S.W. Farran - Designed by W.R. Snapp, 1107 Penn St. N.E."
    - Maps--Richmond (Box-folder 233:3)
      Capitol Area of Richmond, undated; Map of Richmond and Environs, Department of Public Works, 1923; Drawn map of Richmond's North Side.
    - Map of Northern Virginia, Commonwealth of Virginia, 1932, Fairfax County, 1956, Map of Virginia State Highway System, 1924 and of (Box-folder 233:4)
    - Map of United States (Box-folder 233:5)
      Depicts status of women's suffrage (framed and fragile).
    - Map of United States (Box-folder 233:6)
      Suffrage era map - "The Woman Voter and the next President of the United States" - showing which states women can vote and which ones women cannot vote.
    - Maps of Virginia (Box-folder 233:6)
      All with heading of the Virginia League of Woman Voters and labeled as follows: Congressional Districts Organized; Counties having some form of organization; Counties and cities holding citizenship schools; Virginia League of Women voters organized November 10, 1920; Number of Leagues organized; and one unlabeled.
    - Miscellaneous items (Box-folder 233:7)
      Large flyer on which states have compulsory school attendance, 1921; map of Virginia by Virginia Department of Agriculture and Immigration; a chart compiled by Lucia R. Maxwell on International Socialism 1922-1923, showing various woman's organizations; poster of Anchor Line Twin Screw Geared Turbine Steamer named the "California"; Centennial Memorial of United States--Declaration of Independence, published by Baltimore and Ohio Railroad; Victory Liberty Loan poster; anti-war poster; poster of mechanized man and horse; Virginia Society for Human Life poster; League of Women Voters poster "Vote" (2 posters); sheet music: "Votes for Women" - Suffrage Rallying Song.
    - Newspaper pages--full pages of Richmond newspapers, 1920s-1940s (Box-folder 233:8)
      (includes items on women's suffrage; voting habits; a Richmond News-Leader, Suffrage Supplement, and an article on paintings at Richmond Woman's Club; an article by Adèle Clark; several pages of the Richmond Times-Dispatch, November 2, 1933 about the Community Fund; Atlanta Journal, June 12, 1919 article on U.S. Senate passing suffrage amendment; front page of Richmond Times-Dispatch, January 1, 1929, article on what Virginia leaders would like to see in 1929, includes article by Adèle Clark.
    - Photographs--black and white (Box-folder 233:9)
      Majority of the photographs are from the Equal Suffrage League or Virginia League of Women Voters' events. All of these photographs have been reproduced and can be found elsewhere in Series XVII.
    - Posters (Box-folder 233:10)
      Two different posters on the prevention of war; a Department of the Interior, Bureau of Education poster entitled "How and Why to Stand Correctly" 1918; a draft version of a poster by the Equal Suffrage League with typewritten history of suffrage in Virginia and the printed finished copy.
  - Subseries C: Photographs, 1850s-1970s
    - Family photos, approximately 350 photos, 1850s-1970s, [The majority of photos in this box - mostly Equal Suffrage League, Virginia League of Women Voters, and National League of Women Voters photos, approximately 100 photos, n.d., 1910s-1930s - have been re-photographed and have negatives for additional prints. The original photos are located in box 242.] (Box 234 - 238)
    - Adair, Miss Cornelia S. Chairman Education Committee, NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - Baldwin, Mrs. Harris of Washington, D.C., Chairman, Living Costs Committee NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - Baldwin, Mrs. Harris of Washington, D.C., Chairman, Living Costs Committee NLWV Barrett, Dr. Kate Waller, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Beverly, Mrs. F.C. NLV, a League Director, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Catt, Miss Carrie Chapman, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Cheesman, Mrs. James of Providence, RI. Director, First Region NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - Cowper, Mrs. Mary O. Director, Third Region, NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Douglity (?), Miss Annie of NYC, Teacher of Organization and Parliamentary Law at Suffrage School (Box 239, 242)
    - Doyle, Mrs. Henry Grattan, NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Ely, Miss Gertrude NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Fast, Miss Louisa K. Director Dept. of International Cooperation to Prevent War, NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - Gellhorn (?), Mrs. George of St. Louis, Vice-Chairman NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - Hale, Mrs. Beatrice Forbes-Robertson (Box 239, 242)
    - Hauser, Miss Elizabeth Girard, Ohio NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Hauser, Miss Elizabeth J. 4th VP NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Jacobs, Mrs. Solon secretary NLWV Birmingham, Alabama (Box 239, 242)
    - Johnston, Mrs. Meredith, NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Lathrop, Miss Julia Chicago, IL 1st VP NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Ludington, Miss Katharine, Director, First Region, NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - McCulloch, Mrs. Catherine Waugh Chairman, Committee on Uniform Laws Concerning Women, Chicago, ILL (Box 239, 242)
    - McDowell, Mary Miss of Chicago NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - McKelway, Mrs. Ruth S. Director, 3rd Region NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Mead, Mrs. Ernest C. (Box 239, 242)
    - Morgan, Miss Ruth NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Morgan, Miss Ruth 3rd VP NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Morgan, Miss Ruth 3rd VP NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Morgan, Miss Ruth of New York, Chairman of the Committee on International Cooperation to Prevent War, of the NLWV, Miss Morgan was also President of the Colony Club of New York (Box 239, 242)
    - Paige, Mrs. James NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Park, Mrs. Maud Wood President, NLWV, circa 1920-1924 (Box 239, 242)
    - Park, Mrs. Maud of Massachusetts, President, NLWV (found in collection in frame) (Box 239, 242)
    - Parkhurst, Miss Marian I. of Plattsburgh, NY, Congressional Secretary, NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - Shaw, Anna H. (found in collection in frame) (Box 239, 242)
    - Sherwim, Bell President of NLWV, circa 1924 (Box 239, 242)
    - Thompson, Ida Mae, July 1882 (Box 239, 242)
    - Townsend, Mrs. C.E. Norfolk, VA (Box 239, 242)
    - Townsend, Mrs. C.E. president of Norfolk League (?) (Box 239, 242)
    - Townsend, Mrs. Jessie Freemout (?) Easton (?) (Box 239, 242)
    - Turman, Mrs. R.L. Director, NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - Turman, Mrs. R.L. of Atlanta, Georgia, Director 3rd Region, NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - Valentine, Lila Meade (photos in better condition of Valentine located in Box 240) (Box 239, 242)
    - Valentine, Lila Meade (Box 239, 242)
    - Wells, Mrs. Alice Stebbins Los Angeles, CA, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Wells, Mrs. Alice Stebbins (Box 239, 242)
    - ESLV Petition to Virginia General Assembly for Women Suffrage, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Singing the Woman's March on the Capitol Steps at the conclusion of Suffrage Procession, Washington, D.C., May 9, 1914 (Box 239, 242)
    - ESL of Richmond - Parade, Capitol Square, 1916 (Box 239, 242)
    - ESL - Rally on the steps of the State Capital in Richmond, 1914 (Box 239, 242)
    - ESLV, 1919 State Convention Group Photo (Box 239, 242)
    - Unidentified group shot, LWV? (Box 239, 242)
    - Gov. Trinkle signing Sheppard-Townes Act, 1922-1926? (Box 239, 242)
    - Unidentified Suffrage(?) Parade (five photographs) (Box 239, 242)
    - We Fight for Democracy, three unidentified individuals, Foster Studio Portrait (Box 239, 242)
    - ESLV Office photo(?), 1919 (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV - Convention of a New England State or a Regional Conference, 1926 (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV, unidentified woman, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV, Fifth Annual Convention "12 Famous Women Banquet," April 28, 1924 (Box 239, 242)
    - Presidents of State Leagues NLWV, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Equal Suffrage League Headquarters, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - National League of Women Voters - Board of Directors (Box 239, 242)
    - Presidents of State Leagues of Women Voters (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV - Convention, Richmond, VA, 1925 (Box 239, 242)
    - VLWV Convention Delegates, Norfolk, VA, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - LWV "VOTE" poster, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - Convention (?) - Delegates on steps (Box 239, 242)
    - Convention (?) - banquet (Box 239, 242)
    - Brooks, Mrs. Charles (of Kansas, former chairman of NLWV), Morgon, Ruth Miss (3rd VP of NLWV), Clark, Miss Adèle (Virginia, 2nd VP NLWV), Shockley, Alden (Nevada, Director of the Seventh Region of the NLWV) (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV Convention, Jamestown, VA (Box 239, 242)
    - ESL of Virginia, Float in Liberty Bonds Parade, 1918 (Box 239, 242)
    - VLWV Convention in Alexandria - Mrs. Sarah Matthews, Mrs. John H. Lewis, Miss Adèle Clark, Miss Helen Chrisli (?), 1923 (Box 239, 242)
    - Women League of Voters, Charlottesville, Virginia, June 26-27, 1931 (Box 239, 242)
    - VLWV Conference, 1925 (Box 239, 242)
    - Eagles Mere, Pennsylvania (Adèle Clark representing NLWV), 1926 (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV Board of Directors, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV headquarters, Washington, D.C. (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV headquarters, Washington, D.C. (Box 239, 242)
    - Conference on the Causes of War - White House (with President Coolidge), 1925 (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV - group photo, includes Carrie Chapman Catt, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - unidentified woman NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV - Unidentified Women - NLWV (Box 239, 242)
    - ESA - Clark, Adèle; Houston, Nora; Schaill(?), May; Jobson, Mrs Frank, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1916 (Box 239, 242)
    - NLWV - Belle Sherwin and Adèle Clark holding portrait of Mrs. Carrie Chapman Catt (Box 239, 242)
    - VLWV delegation to visit Virginia's U.S. Senators (VA. Historical Society), 1923 (Box 239, 242)
    - ESL Parade, undated (Box 239, 242)
    - LWV - convention (?) (Box 239, 242)
    - Astor, Lady Nancy, Governor's Ball (Box 239, 242)
    - Governor's Ball - World War Honor Roll, 1917-1918 (Box 239, 242)
    - Governor's Ball - World War Honor Roll, 1917-1918 (Box 239, 242)
    - WPA photos, Lila Meade Valentine Memorial photos, Virginia Society for Crippled Children and Handicapped Adults photos, various art related photos, approximately 80 photos, undated, 1910s-1940s (Box 240)
    - Glass Plate negatives, a total of 18, mostly of family members, circa 1900 (Box 241)
    - Original photos that have already been re-photographed (see box 239), mostly of ESL and VLWV. Oversize original photos are located in Map Drawer# 23, file# 9. (Box 242)
    - Art and Science, 1914-1958 (Box 243)
    - Church-Catholic and Hebrew, 1915-1977 (Box 243)
    - Committees, undated, 1920s (Box 243)
    - Correspondence- Envelopes, 1921-1968 (Box 243)
    - Correspondence- Insurance, Cemetery Lots, 1942-1972 (Box 243)
    - Correspondence- Letters, 1917-1966 (Box 243)
    - Elections and Voting, 1920-1954 (Box 243)
    - Hollywood Cemetery, 1912-1915 (Box 243)
    - Horse Clippings,. undated (Box 243)
    - Houston, Emily- Funeral, 1948 (Box 243)
    - League of Women Voters- Richmond, Virginia, and National, 1920-1955 (Box 243)
    - League of Women Voters- Tests, undated (Box 243)
    - Lila Meade Valentine Memorial Association, 1921-1936 (Box 243)
    - Misc., 1916-1928 (Box 243)
    - News Articles- Adèle Clark, 1956-1983 (Box 243)
    - News Articles- Art, 1914-1984 (Box 243)
    - News Articles- Death Notices, 1930-1966 (Box 243)
    - News Articles- Government, 1920-1962 (Box 243)
    - News Articles- Great Virginians, 1931 (Box 243)
    - News Articles- League of Women Voters, 1917-1970 (Box 243)
    - News Articles- Misc., 1921-1965 (Box 243)
    - News Articles- Women's Committees/ Suffrage, 1913-1976 (Box 243)
    - Proposed Bills/Legislature, 1909-1936 (Box 243)
    - School Brochures, 1925-1932 (Box 243)
    - Stencils, undated (Box 243)
    - Suffrage- Women and Blacks/Race Articles, 1913-1956 (Box 243)
    - Women's Who's Who, 1941-1963 (Box 243)